<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Complexity on MitchThinks</title>
    <link>/tags/complexity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Complexity on MitchThinks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/complexity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaos with a pocket calculator.</title>
      <link>/posts/chaos_logistic_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/chaos_logistic_map/</guid>
      <description>1 The logistic map 2 Visualising complexity 2.1 Stable equilibrium 2.2 Period doubling 2.3 Chaos 2.4 Bifurcation diagram  3 Building non-linear intuitions 4 Studying non-elephant animals   div#TOC li { list-style:none; background-image:none; background-repeat:none; background-position:0; }  Most non-fiction books teach you what to think. They give you a new set of facts to trot out when someone brings up pop psychology at the pub or let you feel smug when you ‘explain’ why the Bank of England cut interest rates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nobody goes there anymore. It&#39;s too crowded.</title>
      <link>/posts/el_farol_bar_problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/el_farol_bar_problem/</guid>
      <description>1 Background 2 Model 2.1 Set-up 2.2 R function  3 Simulations 3.1 First glance 3.2 Comparing simulations 3.3 Changing the threshold 3.4 Results  4 Why should you care?   div#TOC li { list-style:none; background-image:none; background-repeat:none; background-position:0; }  I’m currently making my way through Complexity and the Economy by W. Brian Arthur. The book’s second chapter is a paper from 1994 called Inductive Reasoning and Bounded Rationality: The El Farol Problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Wealth (Eric Beinhocker, 2007).</title>
      <link>/posts/origin_wealth_complexity_economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/origin_wealth_complexity_economics/</guid>
      <description>1 Summary 2 Dynamics 3 Agents 4 Networks 5 Emergence 6 Evolution   div#TOC li { list-style:none; background-image:none; background-repeat:none; background-position:0; }  If you want to see the code for this post then you can find the .Rmd file here.
1 Summary In the first section of The Origin of Wealth Beinhocker outlines 5 key differences between traditional (neoclassical) economics and complexity economics:
Dynamics Agents Networks Emergence Evolution  I’ll try to illustrate each in turn (the emphasised summaries heading each section are taken from Beinhocker without adaptation).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>