<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Probability and statistics on MitchThinks</title>
    <link>/tags/probability-and-statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Probability and statistics on MitchThinks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/probability-and-statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow thinking about small samples.</title>
      <link>/posts/small_samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/small_samples/</guid>
      <description>1 Small samples are more extreme 2 Funnel plots to the rescue 3 Stats as slow thinking   div#TOC li { list-style:none; background-image:none; background-repeat:none; background-position:0; }  In 2006, the statistician Howard Wainer and the education researcher Harris Zwerling wrote a short research paper about school size. In it they present two facts about the rate of Kidney Cancer in counties in the US. Do me the favour of pausing after reading each and thinking about how you would explain them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The new statistics: why and how?*</title>
      <link>/posts/the_new_statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the_new_statistics/</guid>
      <description>0.1 Irrelevant differences 1 Research problems 1.1 p-value problems 1.2 Changes in probability    div#TOC li { list-style:none; background-image:none; background-repeat:none; background-position:0; }  If you want to see the code for this post then you can find the .Rmd file here.
0.1 Irrelevant differences Statistical significance is a widely misunderstood concept and I’ll cover the flaws in the null hypothesis significance testing (NHST) approach, of which it is a component, in more detail in a different post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Field Guide to Lies and Statistics (Daniel Levitin, 2016).</title>
      <link>/posts/lies_and_stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lies_and_stats/</guid>
      <description>1 Is the stat plausible? 1.1 Back of the napkin calculations 1.2 You’ve taken a bath before  2 Are the axes leading you astray? 2.1 Truncated axes 2.2 Discontinuous axes 2.3 Elongated axes 2.4 Duplicate axes  3 Dodgy reporting 3.1 Hiding a decrease in the cumulative 3.2 Comparing apples and oranges  4 Conclusion   div#TOC li { list-style:none; background-image:none; background-repeat:none; background-position:0; }  If you want to see the full code for this post then you can find it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability in the real world*</title>
      <link>/posts/probability_real_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/probability_real_world/</guid>
      <description>1 Linda’s birthday 1.1 The Linda problem 1.2 The Birthday puzzle 1.3 Bad intuitions  2 Legal problems 2.1 Ignoring dependence 2.2 The prosecutor’s fallacy 2.3 The Feynman conjecture  3 Health problems 3.1 Base rate neglect    div#TOC li { list-style:none; background-image:none; background-repeat:none; background-position:0; }  1 Linda’s birthday 1.1 The Linda problem  1.2 The Birthday puzzle  1.3 Bad intuitions These are just two examples from many which illustrate how our gut reactions can lead us astray.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>