<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MitchThinks</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MitchThinks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Agent-based modeling: Lizards &amp; Rock, Paper, Scissors</title>
      <link>/interests/abm_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/interests/abm_intro/</guid>
      <description>Agent-based modeling Rock, paper, scissors Side Blotched Lizards   Agent-based modeling Intro.
Use/relevance in complexity economics.
This article was inspired by this post, which I attempted to recreate and extend.
 Rock, paper, scissors Aim: Simulate simple rock, paper, scissors game to visualise a simple evolutionary process.
Simple Game Rules:
 Individuals are organised on a lattice network. Each individual has a strategy (Rock, Paper, Scissors). Each time period we choose one individual at random to play a game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Wealth (Beinhocker 2007): Complexity Economics</title>
      <link>/books/origin_of_wealth_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/origin_of_wealth_1/</guid>
      <description>Critique of Traditional Economics E.g. Sugarscape  1st difference: Dynamics 2nd difference: Agents 3rd difference: Networks 4th difference: Emergence 5th difference: Evolution   Critique of Traditional Economics E.g. Sugarscape   1st difference: Dynamics  Traditional:
 Closed, static, linear systems in equilibrium  Complexity:
 Open, dynamic, non-linear systems far from equilibrium    2nd difference: Agents  Traditional:
 Modeled collectively (homogenous) Use complex deductive calculations to make decisions Have complete information Random errors (no biases) No learning or adaptation (already optimal)  Complexity:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Wealth (Beinhocker 2007): Evolution</title>
      <link>/books/doughtnut_economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/doughtnut_economics/</guid>
      <description>  Design Spaces: From Games to Economies Physical Technology: From Stone Tools to Spacecraft Social Technology: From Hunter-Gatherers to Multinationals Economic Evolution: From Big Men to Markets Redefining Wealth: Fit Order   Design Spaces: From Games to Economies  Physical Technology: From Stone Tools to Spacecraft  Social Technology: From Hunter-Gatherers to Multinationals  Economic Evolution: From Big Men to Markets  Redefining Wealth: Fit Order  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Wealth (Beinhocker 2007): Evolution</title>
      <link>/books/origin_of_wealth_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/origin_of_wealth_2/</guid>
      <description>  Design Spaces: From Games to Economies Physical Technology: From Stone Tools to Spacecraft Social Technology: From Hunter-Gatherers to Multinationals Economic Evolution: From Big Men to Markets Redefining Wealth: Fit Order   Design Spaces: From Games to Economies  Physical Technology: From Stone Tools to Spacecraft  Social Technology: From Hunter-Gatherers to Multinationals  Economic Evolution: From Big Men to Markets  Redefining Wealth: Fit Order  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Field Guide to Lies &amp; Stats (Levitin 2016)</title>
      <link>/books/lies_and_stats_levitin_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/lies_and_stats_levitin_2016/</guid>
      <description>Evaluating Numbers Plausibility Averages Axes Reporting How numbers are collected Probabilities  Evaluating Words Identifying expertise Induction vs deduction    Evaluating Numbers Plausibility Numerical sense checks. Claim: “In the 35 years since marijuana laws stopped being enforced in California, the number of marijuana smokers has doubled every year”.
Even if we start with the most generous estimate that intitially there was 1 marijuana smoker then after 35 years that would give us \(2^{34} (&amp;gt; 17\text{bil})\) smokers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Education I have a B.A. in Biological Sciences from the University of Oxford and an M.Sc. in Behavioural Economics from the University of Essex.
 Employment I currently work as a Junior Data Scientist in the Intelligence Team at a marketing agency called SHARE.
 The Site I built the site using the R package blogdown for a few reasons:
 I wanted to learn the (very) basics of web development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Send me a message on LinkedIn.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>