<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Books on MitchThinks</title>
    <link>/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Books on MitchThinks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Doughnut Economics (Raworth 2017)</title>
      <link>/books/doughtnut_economics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/doughtnut_economics/</guid>
      <description>Summary Illustration 1: Complexity Illustration 2: Growth   Summary Raworth proposes 7 changes to bring economics into the 21st century.
Goal: GDP growth \(\rightarrow\) The Doughnut.   Summarise chapter.  Big Picture: Self contained market \(\rightarrow\) Embedded economy.   Summarise chapter.  Behavioural: Rational economic man \(\rightarrow\) Social, adaptable humans.   Summarise chapter.  Complexity: Mechanical equilibrium \(\rightarrow\) Dynamic complexity.   Summarise chapter.  Inequality: Growth will even it up \(\rightarrow\) Distributive by design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Wealth (Beinhocker 2007): Complexity Economics</title>
      <link>/books/origin_of_wealth_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/origin_of_wealth_1/</guid>
      <description>Summary 1st difference: Dynamics 2nd difference: Agents 3rd difference: Networks 4th difference: Emergence 5th difference: Evolution   Summary In the first section of The Origin of Wealth Beinhocker outlines 5 key differences between traditional (neoclassical) economics and complexity economics:
Dynamics Agents Networks Emergence Evolution  I’ll try to illustrate each in turn (the emphasised summaries heading each section are taken from Beinhocker without adaptation).
 1st difference: Dynamics  Traditional:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of Wealth (Beinhocker 2007): Evolution</title>
      <link>/books/origin_of_wealth_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/origin_of_wealth_2/</guid>
      <description>  Design Spaces: From Games to Economies Physical Technology: From Stone Tools to Spacecraft Social Technology: From Hunter-Gatherers to Multinationals Economic Evolution: From Big Men to Markets Redefining Wealth: Fit Order   Design Spaces: From Games to Economies  Physical Technology: From Stone Tools to Spacecraft  Social Technology: From Hunter-Gatherers to Multinationals  Economic Evolution: From Big Men to Markets  Redefining Wealth: Fit Order  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Field Guide to Lies &amp; Stats (Levitin 2016)</title>
      <link>/books/lies_and_stats_levitin_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/books/lies_and_stats_levitin_2016/</guid>
      <description>Evaluating Numbers Plausibility Averages Axes Reporting How numbers are collected Probabilities  Evaluating Words Identifying expertise Induction vs deduction    Evaluating Numbers Plausibility Numerical sense checks. Claim: “In the 35 years since marijuana laws stopped being enforced in California, the number of marijuana smokers has doubled every year”.
Even if we start with the most generous estimate that intitially there was 1 marijuana smoker then after 35 years that would give us \(2^{34} (&amp;gt; 17\text{bil})\) smokers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>